<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>7 | Ankit Dhall</title>
    <link>https://ankitdhall.github.io/publication_types/7/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ankitdhall.github.io/publication_types/7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>7</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Ankit Dhall</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 15:45:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://ankitdhall.github.io/publication_types/7/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Representations for Images With Hierarchical Labels</title>
      <link>https://ankitdhall.github.io/publication/learning-representations-for-images-with-hierarchical-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 15:45:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ankitdhall.github.io/publication/learning-representations-for-images-with-hierarchical-labels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Image classification has been studied extensively but there has been limited work in the direction of using non-conventional, external guidance other than traditional image-label pairs to train such models. In this thesis we present a set of methods to leverage information about the semantic hierarchy induced by class labels. In the first part of the thesis, we inject label-hierarchy knowledge to an arbitrary classifier and empirically show that availability of such external semantic information in conjunction with the visual semantics from images boosts overall performance. Taking a step further in this direction, we model more explicitly the label-label and label-image interactions by using order-preserving embedding-based models, prevalent in natural language, and tailor them to the domain of computer vision to perform image classification. Although, contrasting in nature, both the CNN-classifiers injected with hierarchical information, and the embedding-based models outperform a hierarchy-agnostic model on the newly presented, real-world ETH Entomological Collection image dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time 3D Pose Estimation with a Monocular Camera Using Deep Learning and Object Priors</title>
      <link>https://ankitdhall.github.io/publication/real-time-3d-monocular-pose-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 18:07:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ankitdhall.github.io/publication/real-time-3d-monocular-pose-estimation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We propose a complete pipeline that allows object detection and simultaneously estimate the pose of these multiple object instances using just a single image. A novel &amp;ldquo;keypoint regression&amp;rdquo; scheme with a cross-ratio term is introduced that exploits prior information about the object&amp;rsquo;s shape and size to regress and find specific feature points. Further, a priori 3D information about the object is used to match 2D-3D correspondences and accurately estimate object positions up to a distance of 15m. A detailed discussion of the results and an in-depth analysis of the pipeline is presented. The pipeline runs efficiently on a low-powered Jetson TX2 and is deployed as part of the perception pipeline on a real-time autonomous vehicle cruising at a top speed of 54 km/hr.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
